DUONG TRUONG GIANG Frontend Developer

0399 559 432 | giangduong.dev@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/giang--duong/

Profile

Hard working and effective web developer who has over 1 year of experience with React and React framework such as Nextjs. I enjoy developing user interface based on customer requirements, meet varying browser and device demands. As a front-end developer. I primarily intergrated Web API, optimatize UX/UI and developed feature for web server-side rendering using Nextjs. Additionally, I have a understanding TypeScript and UI componenst including Ant Desgin, Material UI, Shadon UI,... .I am eager to learn new technologies and methodologies to bring the best value for customer and company.

Skills & Abilities

- · HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, LESS
- · JavaScript, TypeScript, Python.
- · React, NextJs, JQuery.
- · Google Cloud (Firebase).

- · TailwindCSS, Bootstrap 5.
- · Antd, Material UI, Shadon UI.
- · Redux.
- · Git.

Education

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER NETWORK AND DATA COMMUNICATION | TON DUC THANG UNIVERSITY | AUGUST 2018 – OCTORBER 2022

Level - Good

Experience

METAPOLIS COMPANY LIMITED | FRONTEND DEVELOPER | SEPTEMBER 2022 – FEBRUARY 2024

- · Collaborated with back-end team to integrate APIs.
- Built reusable code to utilise for other projects and to minimise costs.
- · Collaborated with designers to implement concept and design of website.
- · Developed and integrated payment processing features onto eCommerce websites.
- · Collaborated with team members to achieve target results.
- Developed designs to meet varying browser and device demands.
- · Participance in code reviews and contribute to the improvement of coding standards.
- · Develop new or expand features in the project.
- · Participance in fix bug within existing features.

APPS CYCLONE TECHNOLOGY JSC | FRONTEND INTERN | FEBRUARY 2022 - APRIL 2022

- · Designed and implemented website interface for mobile, desktop and tablets.
- · Handled special projects designated by senior developer.
- · Designed layout and graphics to enhance aesthetics and appearance of website.

 Researched new programming languages, frameworks and technologies to stay abreast with latest trend.

Projects

PREDIX | METAPOLIS COMPANY LIMITED | FRONTEND DEVELOPER | JULY 2023 - FEBRUARY 2024

- Descriptions: The web app provides multiple game for prediction such as: BO, Market,... In which, user can predict price in future or win/loss between two entities. All of the transaction is transparency becaused of implemented through the blockchain mechanism.
- · Responsibility:
 - + Setup environment and base project.
 - + Built reusable components for project.
 - + Developed features based on specific requirement.
 - + Convert figma file to HTML/CSS and design layout to meet varying browser.
 - + Optimitized app for maximum performance.
 - + Built custom hook to reusable in all of application.
 - + Collaborated with designers to translate UI/UX design into functional web interfaces.
- · Technologies used: HTML5/CSS3, TypeScript, NextJs, TailwindCSS, MUI, Ether, Cloud Firestore.

KOREAN SPORTS GAME | METAPOLIS COMPANY LIMITED | FRONTEND DEVELOPER | MARCH 2023 – AUGUST 2023

- Descriptions: The web application includes many games in many Korean sports, allowing players to choose from a list of more than 1,000 games of diverse genres.
- · Responsibility:
 - + Setup environment and base project for user and admin page.
 - + Participated in pre-project analysis to validate creation of user interface.
 - + Developed features based on specific requirement.
 - + Convert figma file to HTML/CSS and design layout to meet varying browser.
 - + Fixed bug and extend features based on client requirement
 - + Built custom hook to reusable in all of application.
 - + Optimazied web for maximun performance and minimise cost.
 - + Built pagination to minimise data called API to improve UX.
- Technologies used: HTML5/CSS3, SCSS, TypeScript, NextJs, React, TailwindCSS, MUI, Antd, Cloud Firestore.

Certificate

TOEIC | IIG VIET NAM | FEBRUARY 2022 - FEBRUARY 2024

Score: 685